

Software Support Associate seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Project Management, Client Management, Software Installation, Configuration Management



Current Designation: Software Support Associate Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 4 Month(s)

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period Current Company: Amdocs

Current Location: Gurgaon Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Support Associate, Software Developer, Software Development, Application

Programming, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Project Management, Client

Management, Software Installation, Configuration Management

Verified: Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

## **Summary**

My loved one says I'm a bundle of joy, forever. I studied Computer Science because I believe that through technology the efficiency of humans can be increased multifolds. Topics of interest to me are mindsets, behaviors, trust and technology. Putting

all these together I'm on a mission to help corporates by utilizing my skills.

The best piece of technology ever created in this world dates back to 200,000 years ago, it's us Humans. We have the best of audio (ears, vocal) and video (eyes) devices, processing, intelligence (brain), networking (nervous system), and so much more. I love building products that solve big and small problems and make technology feel more human.

I enjoy playing the Bamboo flute and reading about productivity tools and hacks.

Yoga and meditation is a source of inspiration and growth for me.

# Work Experience

Amdocs as Software Support Associate

Jun 2019 to Till Date

Working on Hadoop ecosystem mainly Hive, SQL, HDFS, Sqoop, Spark, Spark SQL, Kafka and Cassandra (No SQL) Design, plan, and develop programs to perform automated extract, transform and load data between data sources when working with large data sets (TBs+ range)

Working with the application team to design and develop an effective Hadoop solution. Be actively engaged and responsible in the development process

Developing and testing workflow scheduler job scripts in Apache Oozie

Proactively, initiate, develop and maintain effective working relationships with team members. Coordinate with all team members, including 3rd party suppliers

**Blackrock** as Analyst May 2018 to Jun 2019

Understanding client's need and working with internal BlackRock's teams to provide relevant and intuitive analysis of Green package Platform using different technology stack (mainly Python, SQL Analytics, Java and Hadoop ecosystem) and knowledge of asset classes mainly fixed income, equity and derivatives

- \* Oracle PL/SQL and writing queries, stored procedures, Indexes, triggers
- \* programming in a Unix/Linux environment, including Java, Python and shell scripting
- \* Working with external vendor technologies, libraries and API such as available from Bloomberg
- \* Assist in troubleshooting issues, support the operation of production software, and handle queries from business teams
- \* Enhancing & designing dashboards / reports with the help of Tableau, Alteryx and KNIME.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi in 2017

#### IT Skills

| Skill Name       | Version Last Used | Experience           |
|------------------|-------------------|----------------------|
| MACHINE LEARNING |                   | 1 Year(s) 2 Month(s) |
| DATA ANALYSIS    |                   | 2 Year(s)            |
| Big Data         |                   | 2 Year(s)            |
| Python           |                   | 2 Year(s)            |
| SQL              |                   | 2 Year(s)            |
| Linux            |                   | 2 Year(s)            |

### Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English  | Proficient  |      |       |       |
| Hindi    | Proficient  |      |       |       |

### **Projects**

Project Title: detection of crime by the help of machine learning

Client: college project

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Feb 2017 - May 2017

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: age,gender,past crime,education,society feedback are the five attributes that are used in this project.WEKA tool is used for clustering.NAIVE-BAYES and K-NN algorithm is used and for further processing in project RANDOM FOREST algorithm is also used.

#### **Affirmative Action**

**Work Authorization** 

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time